I'm very famous for saying never sell
your Bitcoin, and that's why the
internet went crazy when we said we
might sell it.
Trolls on the internet continually
complain that this is a Ponzi scheme
because we sell equity in order to fund
a preferred dividend. Whenever we say we
will never do something, we always
regret it, whatever it is.
We bought more Bitcoin than anybody that
I know of.
>> How has your thesis on Bitcoin changed a
bit?
>> We have bought $200 million of Bitcoin
in an hour, or $300 million in an hour,
and stopped. Price goes up. So, for
anyone that thinks that they have enough
power
>> A lot of investors believe this never
sell your Bitcoin religiously, right?
And do you think they should still
follow that suggestion?
>> We're very pleased to be co-hosting this
exciting interview with executive
chairman of strategy, Michael Saylor.
Co-hosting with me is
>> Bonnie Chang.
>> And we're going to kick it off with some
recent news coming out of strategy's own
announcement and Michael Saylor's
announcement on social media. Take it
away, Bonnie.
>> Something happened 19 hours ago, and
that shocked the internet.
What was it?
>> Uh we probably uh it's probably you're
referring to our earnings call where we
announced that we're prepared to sell
Bitcoin to fund our uh stretch dividends
if need be.
>> And
I'm sure that was a very
well-thought-through
uh pivot.
What is the idea behind it?
>> The most important thing is we want the
market to understand that Bitcoin
capital gains fund stretch credit
dividends.
So, when we sell STRC credit, we sell a
million dollars of it, we turn around,
we buy a million dollars of Bitcoin. We
expect Bitcoin to appreciate about 30% a
year.
It's been appreciating almost 40% a
We strip the first 11%
of that
of that capital gain and we pay that as
a credit dividend. But there's been a
bit of confusion in the market about
where the dividends come from, you know,
how do we pay the dividend?
And for most of the history of the
instrument, we sold common equity, MSTR
equity to pay the dividend.
Um MSTR equity is a derivative of
Bitcoin. It normally trades at premium
to Bitcoin. And so we were selling a
Bitcoin derivative. But some people
worried that we wouldn't be able to sell
the equity in the future and then there
are short narratives that that we have
to sell the equity.
And then there are other narratives that
the company won't sell its Bitcoin and
that kind of metastasized to well, if
they're not going to sell their Bitcoin,
it must not have any value and they can
never sell it and if they can't sell it,
then we can't count the Bitcoin as an
asset on the balance sheet. So if you
had $65 billion worth of something and
people wanted to value it at zero,
it's not very good, right? The we don't
want the credit rating agencies to think
the company has zero dollars of assets.
We want the credit rating agencies to
think we have $65 billion of assets.
And you know, there are also trolls on
the internet that that continually
complain that this is a Ponzi scheme
because we sell equity in order to fund
a preferred dividend. Well, what we want
to do is we want to reinforce the
business model is we sell credit to make
a capital investment in an asset,
Bitcoin, digital capital. The capital
investment of creates over time faster
than the dividend.
We then monetize the capital gain and we
pay the dividend. We think that the best
way to punctuate this, to make it very
clear is to to make the point that the
company doesn't have to sell common
stock ever. We can simply sell highly
appreciated Bitcoin
in order to pay dividend. and if we do
that you're capturing a capital gain to
pay a credit dividend.
I think uh
the analogy is like uh a real estate
development company uh raises capital by
issuing credit instrument, buys land at
$10,000 an acre,
develops it, it's worth $100,000 an
acre,
and then they monetize that capital
appreciation. You could sell the land at
$100,000 an acre, you could rent the
land after you fully developed it, you
could refinance the land,
but nobody questions uh a real estate
development company that makes a capital
investment with a a credit income.
What we're doing is the same thing with
Bitcoin and we want to make sure that
the market understands that. I'm very
famous for saying never sell your
Bitcoin and that's why the internet went
crazy when we said we might sell it,
but uh if I was being more precise, I'd
say never be a net seller of Bitcoin. It
just wouldn't have been so viral or so
catchy to say never be a net seller of
Bitcoin.
I think that in these periods even if we
were to sell one Bitcoin, we'd be buying
10 to 20 more Bitcoin. So you're really
talking about a situation where we buy
10 Bitcoin, sell one Bitcoin,
buy nine net Bitcoin and continue to
accrete Bitcoin. It's it should be a
non-issue after people understand it,
but right now it's a colorful area of
commentary.
>> Is it possible for you to comment how do
you sell one Bitcoin and buy 10?
>> Yeah.
So
the number one Bitcoin accretion engine
is stretch. Uh we sold $3.2 billion of
STRC in uh April.
So we bought $3.2 billion of Bitcoin.
The dividend is about 80 to 90 million.
So in the month when we're raising 3
billion, we're we need to come up with
uh 80 or 90 million dollars to pay the
dividend. So you would be in essence you
would be buying 30 Bitcoin, selling one
Bitcoin.
Right? Our um
our break-even rate
is 2.3%.
So, what that means is that if we sell
stretch if we issue stretch credit uh
equal to 2.3% of our Bitcoin holdings,
then that means we will be a net buyer
of Bitcoin forever even if we sell
Bitcoin to pay the dividend. Another
point is that if Bitcoin appreciates
2.3% a year,
we can pay the dividends forever.
Right? And and continue to grow value,
right? And we can do it without selling
any any common equity. So, the
break-even is 2.3. Right now where we've
um sold about $5
of STRC in the first 4 months of the
year.
So, we're running on a pace uh to the
issuance rate of 15 or 20% this year.
2.3% is the break-even.
So,
you buy 20, you sell two, you net 18,
right? The The company as long as it
grows is going to buy more Bitcoin than
it sells. I expect we'll be a net buyer
of Bitcoin in every month and every
quarter going on forever.
>> One last question before I pass it on to
David.
>> A lot of investors
believe this never sell your Bitcoin
religiously, right? And do you think
they should still follow that
suggestion?
>> Yeah, I think that you should be a net
accumulator of Bitcoin. Like when I say
never sell your Bitcoin, I mean make
sure that if you were to spend it on
something, you replenish it in the time
you spend it. So, there are there also a
lot of crypto people or a lot of Bitcoin
people that say they want to spend
Bitcoin to buy things. And if you were
to spend Bitcoin, I would say just
replenish the Bitcoin. So, you don't
want to be a net seller of Bitcoin
because Bitcoin is capital. You want to
You want to end every year with more
Bitcoin than you started the year. And
the analogy I'd give you is is if Google
spent a billion dollars
to invest in data centers so that they
could make $10 billion.
They're making net $9 billion.
It wouldn't crash the dollar market,
right? Oh, Google spent dollars.
Google sold dollars to buy data centers.
The dollar would be fine. It wouldn't
undermine the Google business model. Oh,
they spent a billion dollars to invest
in their business. That's fine.
Right? And so, it'd be fine for Google.
It's a rational thing to do. Sometimes
you spend money to make more money. So,
if you're spending one Bitcoin to make
10 Bitcoin, I think it's fine for
Bitcoin. I think it's fine for the
company.
I think it strengthens our company
because
if our company has the ability to tap
the crypto liquidity market, if we can
raise liquidity by selling spot Bitcoin,
that's a $20 billion spot market and a
$50 billion derivative market every day.
That's a powerful energy source. So, we
want to be able to to tap that market
when the equity capital markets aren't
as liquid as the as the commodity market
for Bitcoin.
And And so, whenever a company strips
its options, whenever we say we will
never do something, we always regret it,
whatever it is.
Give you another example, right? If we
say we would never ever buy our stock,
we would always sell our stock, then
short sellers would sell our stock, and
they would sell it down to a dollar. The
stock trades at a a big discount to NAV,
we would buy it back. Then the short
sellers have something to lose, then we
would make a lot of money by them being
irrational. And so, what we did say in
our earnings call yesterday is we're
prepared to trade stretch for the common
stock. We'll trade STRC for MSTR. We'll
trade BTC for MSTR.
We will fund our obligations with BTC or
MSTR.
We'll do whatever is in the best
interest of the company.
But, you know, over time we expect to be
a net Bitcoin accumulator. It That
doesn't change. The way that we trade
our assets day-to-day, whether we sell
credit or sell equity or sell capital
assets, that will be a function of of
the market and mispricings. And if
you know, the other thing we said
yesterday is we're ready to buy our
bonds back. So, our our corporate bonds
trade cheap. They're undervalued. And
so, it makes sense for us to buy them.
It doesn't make sense to sell them. So,
we don't sell assets that are
undervalued. We buy assets that are
undervalued. And then, we arbitrage
whatever the inefficiency is. And
if the market knows we're going to do
that, then the market's going to
actually fairly value all those assets.
And that's to the benefit of all the
investors in all those instruments. And
ultimately, that's our fiduciary
obligation.
>> To the skeptics and as you would call
trolls out there who call this a Ponzi
scheme, they're not here to address you.
Let me just read one of your tweets so
you can address them directly. One of
your biggest critics, Peter Schiff,
wrote this morning, "Yesterday Saylor
admitted MSTR would sell Bitcoin if
needed to pay the dividend on STC RC. I
think that type of commitment is needed
to keep the so-called Ponzi going
longer. But my guess is when the time
comes, he's sus- he would suspend the
dividend and crash STC RC rather than
crash Bitcoin." Your response?
>> Peter thinks Bitcoin's a Ponzi scheme.
But But Peter is not really a lover of
anything in this space. Bitcoin is
digital capital. And And we've created a
digital treasury company by selling
equity and credit instruments to buy
capital. I think that Bitcoin is going
to continue because it represents
economic wealth and tokenized form with
full property rights for the world. And
we have built a credit instrument STRC
on top of it which simply strips the
volatility,
reduces the risk, and extracts or
distills a yield
from digital capital.
If you don't acknowledge Bitcoin as
legitimate,
you'll never acknowledge any derivative
on top of it as legitimate.
But for those people that believe that
Bitcoin is digital capital as a as a
store of economic wealth and tokenized
form,
then what we're doing is very
straightforward. We over collateralize
it and for every $5 of Bitcoin, we sell
a dollar of credit.
And the dollar of credit has a defined
yield.
And there are a lot of people that
they believe Bitcoin is a legitimate
asset. They just can't stand the
volatility. It They They don't want to
take money they need for their kids
tuition in the fall and invest it in
Bitcoin because they need to pay a bill
in 12 weeks.
And so for them, digital credit makes a
lot of sense because
the principal is protected, it's stable,
and then they're getting paid three or
four times a money market. And it's the
superior aspects of Bitcoin over other
capital assets which allow us to pay
that superior dividend yield.
>> This is a theory that I'd like to run by
you and I'll pass it back to Bonnie. So,
some traders have noted that whenever
STRC issues a dividend, the ex-dividend
price trades below par for
some period of time, maybe a day or two.
And then once it reaches par, that's
when my that's when strategy goes and
buys Bitcoin. So, they start to front
running that pattern by buying Bitcoin
right before SIRC reaches par, believing
you and strategy would buy Bitcoin at
par.
Can you comment on this?
>> What happens as we approach the dividend
date is there's a massive demand to buy
SIRC because there's like a 90 cent
dividend after that record date. So,
there are billions and billions of
dollars of trading in SIRC leading up to
it and then the day after that record
date, it trades down 60 cents or 70
cents and then it gradually recovers
back to par over the next week or two.
So, that's normal. Those are
arbitrageurs. Their idea is
I want to commit a million dollars of
capital for one day
>> Yeah.
>> and I'm effectively I'm capturing 42%
annual yield a year by having my capital
tied up 12 days a year or something and
they've got their math.
That's fine. It's good for us because it
creates creates liquidity and engagement
and that will continue.
Um
as for the second idea, can you front
run that in the Bitcoin market? Well,
the Bitcoin derivatives market's 50
billion dollars a day and so do I think
someone has enough capital to move that
market? Not really. My my opinion there
is
Bitcoin is is kind of like tech capital
squared and so the things that drive the
Bitcoin market are trade wars
hot wars, foreign policy, the state of
the state in the Strait of Hormuz and
the Iran situation.
And then
currency wars, you know, whether or not
we're expecting SOFR to fall to 200
basis points
and or or whether the yield curve is is
being bent and you can see right now
we're in a
fairly restrictive monetary environment.
So, those macro factors are the primary
driver of Bitcoin. I can tell you for a
fact, for example,
we bought a hundred million dollars of
Bitcoin an hour.
It doesn't move the price.
We bought two hundred million dollars of
Bitcoin an hour. It doesn't move the
price. We have bought two hundred
million dollars of Bitcoin an hour or
three hundred million in an hour and
stopped, the price goes up.
Okay, so for anyone that thinks that
they have enough power, well, I don't
maybe if you're going to bring thirty
billion dollars to the market in one
afternoon, maybe, but I have spent lots
of money. I We bought more Bitcoin than
anybody that I know of. We think I think
we probably acquired sixty-two billion
dollars of Bitcoin. What I believe is
that it's a global market. It's got
dynamics, you know, all its own. It's
driven by foreign policy and if the
Chinese government has a certain
announcement that drives the price of
Bitcoin.
And so
it's flattering
to suggest that we're that systemically
important. I don't think so.
>> Why is it that you buy so much Bitcoin
and you said the price doesn't move?
>> The market's very liquid. It's extremely
liquid.
You know, if
again, so let's say I had a big day and
I bought a billion dollars. Well, a
billion dollars is 1/50 of 50 billion.
If you If you talk to the traders,
they'll say that
the spot market's 20 billion, but the
derivatives is 80 billion sometimes.
So, what's a hundred million dollars in
a
40, 50, 60 billion dollar bucket? It's
like
It's a very deep liquid market. It's the
world's deepest, most liquid capital
market.
Right? That's what makes it special.
On the weekend, you want to put a
billion dollar trade on with 20X
leverage, you can do it in Bitcoin. You
want a billion dollars of credit in an
hour, you can do it in Bitcoin.
It's a very deep market. Uh and I do
think macro factors drive it.
And sometimes it's got a life of its
own.
I think micro factors drive it. I mean,
the
the industry factors are like the
formation of digital credit, the
formation of bank credit and and uh
investor sentiment with regard to
digital assets and those drive it as
well.
But I think that it's greater than all
of us and that's actually why we have
confidence in it because there is no one
actor that's either supporting it or
holding it back.
>> Yeah, the straight-off convoys remains
closed for the foreseeable future. A few
forces will be at play. First,
inflationary forces, some say, will will
remain. Second, the Fed um
will probably need to lower interest
rates at some point. But they're stuck
by higher inflation. So, what happens to
liquidity? Ultimately, what happens to
uh Bitcoin if the Fed remains stuck?
>> I think when you have a
when you have tight monetary policy, uh
high tensions in in uh global trading
and and high geopolitical tensions due
to foreign policy or or wars, whether in
the Ukraine or Iran, all those are
somewhat constrictive and they're
headwinds.
And I think when they reverse, they
become tailwinds.
But Bitcoin will grind up regardless and
that's because there's about 10 to 12
billion dollars a year in organic supply
from the miners. 450 Bitcoin a day, so
figure it out.
And then every every time we come up
with another 10 billion dollars of
capital, we buy the entire year supply.
And so, if a bank creates 10 billion
dollars of credit, that's one turn on
the axle. If we sell 10 billion dollars
of STRC, of digital credit, that's the
second turn on the axle.
When 10 billion dollars flows into IBIT,
that's the third turn on the axle. So,
the capital flows in digital credit and
uh you know, in digital capital wrappers
and bank credit, all of those things are
the driving the fundamentals of the
market and those are all positive and
you're going to see continued adoption
there regardless of the macro factors.
Just the macro winds, they you know,
when we're grinding up 30%, we surged to
50% and when there's a headwind it'll
somewhat slow us down.
>> Has your thesis on Bitcoin changed a
bit?
>> Uh it hasn't changed, um
but I will say this, it's clear that
Bitcoin is digital capital
and one thing that's become clear over
the last 12 months is that at least one
of the killer apps of Bitcoin is digital
credit.
So people are wondering, you know, what
is the killer app of uh a $1.5 trillion
asset class that trades tens of billions
a day and the answer is as collateral
for credit.
So if the digital capital is the highest
performing capital asset
and it is, right? It's outperforming the
S&P by a factor of two to three.
Then it stands to reason that we can
create the highest performing credit
asset on top of that capital asset.
And what we've seen
uh in the last year is
stretches the most liquid credit
instrument. It's the most liquid
preferred stock in the entire market.
It's the biggest preferred stock in the
market. It has the highest sharp ratio.
So we've managed to create an instrument
with a wall of three with performance of
a 11.5% dividend yield, a sharp ratio of
two and a half to three.
The highest credit instrument sharp
ratio is 0.5. The highest sharp ratio on
an equity is Nvidia, it's like 1.7.
The highest sharp ratio you would get
with any other asset is like 0.9 on the
S&P or 0.85 on Bitcoin. None of them
beat one and then the best hedge funds
you find can't do a sharp ratio of more
than 2.2. So digital credit is actually
got a better risk-adjusted return than
every other financial strategy and every
every publicly trading instrument in the
public capital markets. 12 months ago I
couldn't tell you that.
But, uh it's it makes sense that
if Bitcoin is the highest performing
capital, then convertible bonds backed
by Bitcoin become the best performing
convertible bonds. And credit
instruments like stretch become the best
performing preferred stocks.
By the way,
do you know what percentage of the
preferred stock market we are this year?
>> I would assume over 70.
>> We issued 60% of all the preferred stock
in the United States
>> Wow.
>> this year. And we are the largest issuer
of credit in the entire United States
last year and this year. We have
revitalized the preferred stock market,
right? It's exploded. So, I think what's
new is the idea that digital capital
drives digital credit.
And what you'll see as the show is that
digital credit is the stepping stone for
for digital currency or digital money
because there's an explosion of yield
coins.
Tokens that are stable, pegged to the
dollar, that pay you 8% or 9% yield.
Apex has created one. It's gone from
zero to 300 million dollars in like 8
weeks.
Uh Saturn has created another one. It's
gone from zero to 110 million dollars in
6 weeks. There's an explosion of
innovation in the digital asset space
and the crypto space and the tradfi
space uh that's all being driven by
digital credit and Bitcoin is the thing
that makes digital credit possible. And
And that is probably the most exciting
thing happening this year.
>> My final question I'll pass to Bonnie to
close off. Several Bitcoin miners have
already started pivoting their AI data
center to power their data centers.
Are you considering joining this
so-called AI pivot movement if you want
to call it a movement? And if so, how
would you participate?
>> I think it's great that
Bitcoin miners now are able to to
benefit from investment in high
performance, high powered compute, we
created digital credit with digital
intelligence, right? So, how does AI
affect our business? We never could have
created stretch without AI. I I used AI
to to create strike, strife, stride, and
stretch. When we created this digital
credit, what did we do?
We took a block of digital capital.
That's what Bitcoin is. It's just pure
financial energy. We used digital
intelligence
to machine a digital credit with a
certain risk profile, a certain
volatility profile, of a certain yield,
a certain currency profile.
And we took that public in the market.
And I I think that if you're a Bitcoin
treasury or digital treasury company,
the smartest thing you can use is use
digital intelligence to carve out
digital credit from digital capital. And
that is the stepping stone. It's like
the financial fuel
to create digital money and digital
yield. And the marketplace for digital
money and digital yield is a hundred
trillion dollars and it's spreading
virally right now.
>> Last question. Uh Have a spacesuit, will
travel inspired you to go to MIT?
Let's go back to before MIT, before this
book, before Bitcoin.
Tell something to your younger self.
>> You know, uh when I was in first grade,
my parents uh wanted to motivate me and
they told me they'd give me 10 cents for
every book I read. And I had this comic
book addiction. And they And comic books
cost 25 cents as I recall. So, the
calculus was I had to read two and a
half real books to get one comic book.
And I was very motivated, so I read
about a hundred books that summer. And
then I And you know, I'd go to the
library and I'd check out 10 books at a
time and I would take them back when we
had libraries, you know?
And uh I would go read them and then I
discovered science fiction and I I
discovered Heinlein and Clark and Asimov
all
you know, I I read uh The Moon Is a
Harsh Mistress and I read Have Spaceship
Will Travel and
that was all by By third grade, I'd you
know, I'd riffle through them all third
or fourth grade. And I would I would uh
say that reading all this science
fiction drove my intellectual
development. Kids in elementary school,
boys in elementary school are quite
impressionable.
And what I do recall in Have Spaceship
Will Travel is it's a alpha male, he
fixes up a spacesuit, he gets picked up
by a spaceship, he gallivants across the
universe, he saves the human race from
bug-eyed monsters, you know, he returns
back to the United States or to the
Earth and the reward for having saved
the human race from bug-eyed monsters he
he he gets a full tuition scholarship to
MIT. And I figured if MIT was good
enough for the guy that saved the human
race, it was probably good enough for
me. And so, gosh darn it, I was going to
go there.
>> If Elon Musk invited you to go to Mars,
would you would you accept?
>> It depends upon the vehicle he was
offering to take me in.
>> Thank you, Michael.
>> Thank you very much. I appreciate your
time. We Our audience appreciates you.